all right we got to talk about Apple
intelligence so Apple's made this
promise this huge thing is coming that's
going to change everything across their
whole lineup they've been talking about
it for a while and I think that promise
is starting to fade this was first
announced at WWDC 2024 that was nearly 6
months ago and it's still not completely
out yet the new iPhones launched in
September with exactly zero Apple
intelligence features but then some
software updates have started to push
out and eventually it's supposed to be
finished and in everyone's Hands by
March
2025 that's a lot of buildup so what I
want to do now is review every single
Apple intelligence feature that's out so
far and then also get into whether the
promise that they're actually making is
even good in the first place so first up
writing tools so all these features
unless otherwise specified are on iPhone
iPad and Mac so no apple intelligence
features at all on the Vision Pro their
most futuristic platform that's already
kind of fascinating but the writing
tools you may have heard about these
since they're definitely referenced a
lot maybe the most out of any of these
and yes it's basically generative AI to
help adjust what you've already written
so this is easiest to demo on the Mac
but basically you have something you've
written you highlight all of it and then
select one of the writing tools and
actually this is one of the first weird
hiccups just a strangely repetitive UI
you can access any of the writing tools
in one click right here or hit show
writing tools which again shows the same
list of writing tools okay so I suppose
there's a world where you know you write
some message to someone and you just
want it to be a little more friendly or
maybe you've typed out a bunch of stuff
that needs to be sent in a work email so
you want to get the AI to make it more
professional for you sure I guess so
I've run it through various things that
I've written from you know whole video
scripts to just a bunch of messages and
it works technically I think the the
friendly mode mostly uses like shorter
sentences and lots of exclamation points
and then the professional mode kind of
does the opposite like it's it's still
pretty tur but never uses exclamation
points I think maybe concise is the most
useful basically it takes whatever you
highlight and makes it maybe 40% shorter
and then you can hit copy or just
directly replace it if you trust it and
each of these things takes about 3 or 4
seconds to generate entirely on device
so it works offline as well the proof
reading is nice because it picks up on
extra things like capitalization and
proper nouns if you really need that on
top of the auto punctuation checker and
then summary or make table would be
really nice for like really large
documents but it doesn't seem to want to
work on some of my huge documents that
would be nice to summarize or make into
a table so unfortunately even as a
basically a professional writer at this
point I haven't gotten much use out of
writing tools at all so notification
summaries this one to me personally I
have found almost useless basically it
does exactly what it sounds like it does
when it's enabled it summarizes your
notifications from each app so if you
get a long message from someone or
several notifications in a row from a
single app it will do its best to
condense that all into a single message
to help you kind of get the gist quickly
so no matter how long or how short the
messages are whether it's just a text or
maybe a group chat has absolutely blown
up and you missed a 100 messages it's
going to try to summarize all that into
one or two lines the thing is once I
enable it and started using it it it
basically seems like the notifications
that I'm getting are almost never
benefited from being summarized or
shortened like I've never gotten four
text messages that are perfectly
summarized into a single one and I'm
sure it's possible there are going to be
some instances where it works for people
but it's not just me I've seen lots of
examples online and there's plenty of
memes too of Apple's notification
summaries doing some sometimes hilarious
work some BR stuff so it works and I
guess it's good for a laugh once in a
while but yeah this is a feature I
straight up turned off then gen mooji so
okay believe it or not there was some
hype for this one and once again it's
basically exactly what it sounds like
it's it's letting you generate any Emoji
using AI anything you want so let's say
I'm in messages and I want to react to
some message with a very specific emoji
that doesn't exist you would describe an
emoji so you write your text and then
hit create a new Emoji give it about 3
seconds again and it will use generative
AI to create that image for you that's
fun I guess and yes it will sometimes
refuse to make what you ask of it if you
ask for something like crazy or graphic
although it seems to have no problem
making a potato with a gun so that's an
emoji reaction you can send sick it's a
very specific use case there's no doubt
some people will have fun with it I just
think I'm not in the Target demographic
to use this sort of thing all the time
so again over my head cool it exists but
that's it so then image playground is
another maybe kind of weird one this is
almost the same tool but sort of
Standalone this is a playground to
generate images in a cartoon
style of whatever you want so you open
the playgrounds app and again just
describe the image you want in text
anything really but before you type
anything there are also a number of
these buttons down here and they're kind
of just inspiration suggestions for
things or people to include in the image
so yes you can choose any of the people
that your phone recognizes from your
photos app and that'll be the starting
point for the image and then add some
themes or accessories or background or
props or whatever on top of it so here's
me with a hard hat on at a disco and it
generates it again in a few seconds on
device always cartoon style never photo
realistic and it can give you a few
options to choose from and once you hit
done you can copy and paste that image
wherever you want Google and a few
others have this on their devices too
just sort of a playground to make some
artificially generated images again it's
of debatable usefulness of course it
makes sense that it won't do
photorealistic images because that would
open up a whole can of worms uh but it's
even supposed to not do some things that
could potentially be offensive again
like if you ask it for a gun it
typically refuses but I found if you add
a few more variables like a chef hat and
some fireworks to something then it will
be a little more likely to actually pull
through for you so yeah good thing it
says it's in beta and may create
unexpected results this is yet another
app that they've added to my phone that
I predict that I will probably never use
again after making this video so then
priority notifications so okay now this
is one that I think had some promise or
at least I'm in the Target demographic
for it because as an iPhone and Android
User you start to notice that Apple's
weakness has a long time than
notification management if it was just
kind of had a fire hose of notifications
coming in all the time so priority
notifications surfaces certain
notifications Above the Rest when you're
in a focus mode that reduces
notifications but this should also work
in the mail app to put AI identified
high priority messages up at the top
plus some other categories so if you use
the default mail app which I don't but a
lot of people do then this could be
helpful something Gmail has had for many
years and the reduced notifications mode
mod also specifically tries to do a good
job of only letting important
notifications through but keeping the
rest quiet so then the photos app uh yes
we all hate the new photos app everyone
you do I do everyone you know hates it
we're all on the same page it's terrible
but Apple has added exactly one AI
feature to the photos app and in an age
where lots of companies are comfortable
adding a ton of AI to their photos apps
dozens of things but they've decided all
right yeah we can do the background
object removal thing
we can do that so basically the same
thing as Google's Magic Eraser tool
let's say you've got a picture with a
subject in the front and you just want
to remove that annoying thing in the
background you hit the edit button and
then on the right side you hit the
cleanup tool and a lot of times it will
automatically highlight in this sort of
rainbow glow the thing that it auto
detects that you want to remove but if
it doesn't you can just tap or Circle
whatever you want and it takes a few
seconds and then it just gets rid of it
and use a generative fill to fill in the
background and of course some scenes
work better than others it's kind of the
same deal as Magic Eraser or photoshop
typically patterns or repeating
backgrounds will give you the best
results I'm going to say I actually
think this one works better than Google
it's better at getting a good outline of
the photob bomber or the background
object in a single gesture which is nice
it's really smart so to me this is also
one of the more useful features
recording summaries so okay this one had
promise but then was kind of confusing
to me because when I saw it on the list
I was like oh this I would have loved
this as a student this is amazing just
one place where you can record things
transcribe them and then summarize them
and keep them for later that sounds
amazing but this is not built into the
default voice memos app at all so if
you're on a phone call you can turn on
call recording you hit that little
button down there it'll take a second
it'll warn the person that you're on the
phone with with a little message this
call will be recorded and then from
there it'll record everything that gets
said and transcribe it and the
transcriptions are amazing it identifies
each speaker it is accurate I love this
part but then if you care about the
summary part this is where it starts to
get weird again because you go into the
notes app this is where it's saving
everything and it shows up as a new note
and the preview actually summarizes it
right here pretty well but then when you
click in there's a whole transcript
great and then there's another summary
button up here at the top you hit that
and there's a different summary uh and
this one's a little worse the first one
back in the preview actually picked up
and included that I said Ridge wallet
the second one didn't get that at all
but did get best bu interesting but
Apple why don't you bring this to The
Voice Memos app this is I I want to be
able to sit this down in a lecture or a
meeting and have it record things so I
can summarize them later that's like the
main place I figured this would be
useful but it's not there so please
please the only way to initiate this
right now is actually to go through the
notes app to create a new note and then
attach and then create a new recording
and then record your audio into there
but it just feels like it could be one
step easier so okay visual visual
intelligence so these last two are kind
of the big ones visual intelligence is
only available on the iPhone 16 and 16
Pro and you get to it by long pressing
that button on the side of those new
phones which opens it up it's that
camera control button and when you open
it up you get a full screen viewfinder
with three buttons a shutter in the
middle then ask on the left and search
on the right so if you point this at any
object or subject and you hit ask that
lets you ask chat GPT anything about
what it sees and if you hit SE search
then it's basically just reverse Google
image searching whatever it sees so chat
gbt or Google so if you hit the shutter
button it snaps a photo and then
continues to give you those two items or
a popup menu where you can again either
search or ask again pretty repetitive if
you ask me but okay while this is a very
pretty UI and it works pretty quickly it
also isn't anything you know
particularly new that we haven't seen
before like I was just watching my
Galaxy S8 review from back in 2017 where
I do a demo of the exact same thing I
take a picture of something in front of
me it looks it up with Bixby Ai and it
could tell you if it was a landmark or a
product that you could shop for this is
going to be more capable obviously chat
GPT has a lot more capabilities and
maybe even a little bit more trust these
days than Bixby had back then and it's
certainly more well integrated but yeah
so it's not something mind-blowing or
groundbreakingly new but it is ideally
more accurate and more capable than
before maybe they're going to continue
to build on top of this in the future
but then there is chat GPT integration
the sort of last but not least new thing
that Siri works with chat GPT I think a
lot of people thought there was a lot
more to Siri like right off the bat
because it has this new animation and
you see the new Siri animation so you
think it's the new Siri but most of the
new Siri stuff isn't here yet but the
chat GPT stuff is so if you ever make a
request or ask a question that's out of
the normal scope of Siri maybe ask for a
recipe or you ask for it to make a trip
itinerary or something big then it
recognizes it and it can prompt you if
you want to ask chat GPT instead and if
you confirm then it pulls from chat GPT
to respond uh this is all free you don't
need an account for this Apple has
promised all sorts of masking so your
data is not used for training models
open AI doesn't get to collect any of
this information about you through the
requests but you can also sign into your
chat GPT account if you want to keep a
history of your queries or use higher
end model
or even go over the daily limit of free
queries there's even actually a button
to upgrade to chat GPT plus built into
iOS now so it's pretty well considered
so yeah the new Siri animation might be
fooling some people but really it's
other than being able to type to Siri
more easily there's really not a whole
lot actually new yet with Siri but that
brings me to the rest of the things that
aren't here yet still that are coming
soon with software updates that list is
right here there are more Apple int
elligence features that are in the works
coming soon and honestly Siri is the
main one I'm interested in because it's
supposed to be able to take inapp
actions it should be able to reach into
Apps and take action inside of them
which I think could be awesome I think
developers could all update their apps
to work really well with it and it could
be really useful it could differentiate
Siri to actually make it useful again um
but yeah that's still coming but yeah
then from there my take is the rest of
the AI stuff really not super amazing or
compelling to me just to be real like
the writing tools that seems like a nice
safe use of generative AI that's the
thing they're sort of talking about the
most but I don't even find myself
needing to rewrite things that often and
like I said I'm not in the Target
demographic to use the image playgrounds
all that much or gen Emojis all the time
the visual intelligence is definitely
super useful like three or four times a
year for me like when some interesting
plant or dog or whatever is in front of
me and I want to just figure out what it
is but that's actually funny you
remember the the clip from the Apple
keynote of that person who walks up to a
dog and instead of asking the person
walking the dog what kind of dog it is
they just go hey can I take a picture of
your dog and then they ask the phone
what kind of dog it is instead of just
asking the person and that to me is the
perfect encapsulation of so many of
these Apple intelligence features you
could use them and they might work
really well but should you should you
like you can ask for a more friendly
version version of this letter to send
to your
friend or you could try to write it in a
friendly way in the first place
like like you can ask Chachi PT to plan
a whole trip for you with an itinerary
and everything and honestly it's really
impressive when it works but are you
actually going to just go in blind and
just follow the AI generated itinerary
if you even like packing like I know
there's two types of people when packing
maybe some people will just follow the
AI generated prompt but I feel like I'm
in the type that kind of wants a little
bit more than that I think luckily no
matter what I'm packing it always fits
in my Ridge travel gear so shout out to
Ridge for sponsoring this portion of the
video specifically I helped design the
new commuter bag for Ridge and I
actually I've been dailying this
creation for the past couple months we
got it some really good water bottle
holders on the sides now and I also
added a tablet sleeve in the back so if
you've got a tablet and a laptop they
both have their own padded slot and then
I double down when I'm flying because I
also have the ridge c car on which is
basically perfect it's weatherproof it's
rugged it's got you know these aluminum
corner protectors it also has the 360
spinning wheels they're super smooth of
course it has a slot for a Tracker in
case it's ever separated from you it's
incredibly lightweight it's the go-to
and you already know that they work
perfectly together like a little
ecosystem to create a perfect little
travel combo so shout out to Ridge for
sponsoring this portion of the video and
for letting me design some of these
products and some more that are upcoming
so you have to stay tuned for those uh
but if you want to pick up both the
carry-on and the backpack you can get
them together at ridge.com MKBHD and get
30% off and they also have their Black
Friday sell going on right now but yeah
I think apple is going to build on and
sort of iterate on hopefully all of
these features like we have the sort of
standard set that we're expecting from
them now and this is this is the worst
they'll ever be they will only get
better from here but it is pretty crazy
to see how much emphasis is in all of
the advertising and all the talk about
the newest devices on apple.com as if
Apple intelligence is this massive
gamechanging groundbreaking new thing
you know there are parts of it that are
really good I think the background
eraser tool in photos is probably the
best we've seen it's better than
Google's it's really impressive I think
the visual intelligence stuff has
potential to be really good but honestly
the best thing I think we've gotten from
Apple intelligence cuz all the stuff is
running on device is bumping up the base
memory in everything there's more RAM in
every iPhone now and the base memory on
every Mac is 16 gigs now which made the
base Mac Mini an incredible deal so
shout out to Apple intelligence for that
either way hopefully a lot more coming
thanks for watching catch you guys in
the next one peace
[Music]