hey everybody and welcome to day six
before we get into today's news I want
to acknowledge that we had a few hours
of downtime yesterday we know you depend
on us and we're really sorry for the
interruption uh we take this super
seriously and the teams are working on a
detailed postmortem that we're going to
post later today uh but the good news is
we're back we're fully operational and
we've got a couple of exciting things
for you right now uh the first we're
going to keep secret and we'll show you
in a little bit the second is that we're
excited to announce that we're bringing
video to Advanced voice mode so you can
bring live video and uh also live screen
sharing into your conversations with
chat GPT and the best way I know how to
do this is to just show it to you so uh
I'm going to go into uh into chat GPT
and you'll see the normal advanced voice
mode button on the bottom right of the
composer I click
it and uh as it loads here we'll give
this one more
try there we go all right so you can see
as we as we go into there there's now a
couple more buttons on the bottom left
in particular there's this video
button and so here we are and I can I'm
going to introduce myself hey Chad I'm
Kevin I lead product at open
a hi Kevin it's great to meet you what
can I I help you with today well
actually I'd love to introduce you to a
few of my colleagues does that sound
good sure I'd love to meet them all
right hey chat I'm Michelle and I'm an
engineer on the Chachi BT multimodal
team hi Michelle it's nice to meet you
an engineer on the chat GPT multimodal
team that sounds exciting it is thanks
hi chat I'm Jackie and I'm the product
lead for Chach PT
multimodal hi Jackie it's great to meet
you too sounds like you're all working
on some really cool projects we really
are hey chat GBC I'm Rowan I'm a
researcher here at open aai on
multimodal hi Rowan it's nice to meet
you multimodal research sounds
fascinating all right and now I want to
see if you remember the folks that you
met so can I give you a quick
quiz sure I'm ready for a quiz all right
what what was the name of my colleague
that was wearing the reindeer
antlers that would be Michelle
all right and how about the name of my
colleague that was wearing the Santa
hat that would be Rowan all right good
work you're two for two you get an A
thanks
chat thanks Kevin this was fun let me
know if
there we are so excited to start the
roll out of video and screen share in
advanced voice today we know this is a
long time coming so to recap you can
already talk with advanced voice and
chaty PT out loud just like you would a
cooworker or a friend advanced voice
uses our natively multimodal 40 model
that means it takes in your audio
directly understands it and outputs
audio directly as a result conversations
with advanced voice have a much more
natural conversation Pace with a depth
of emotion and tone across more than 50
languages starting today and over the
course of the next week we'll be rolling
out video and screen share in advanced
voice so that you can share realtime
visual content with chubbt to make your
conversations even richer and more
useful and here's Rowan to show us more
about what it can do yeah so now you can
chat with chat gbt over video and voice
together in real time you can ask for
help troubleshoot or use it to learn
something new so in fact I'm going to
try testing out right now I'm going to
have it uh teach me how to make pourover
coffee so I'm going to grab a couple of
materials
here grab this and that and then I'm
going to fire up a new conversation with
chat
gbt and hit the advanced voice mode icon
on the lower
right and then once it connects I'll
share my video hey chat how's it
going I'm doing great thanks for asking
I see you're wearing a Santa hat I am
and do you see what I have in front of
me yes I see a coffee set up with a
kettle and a dripper are you planning to
make some coffee I'd love to do you
think you could walk me through the
steps
sure I'd love to first place a filter in
the dripper and rinse it with hot water
to eliminate any papery taste this also
warms up the dripper and the mug great
so then what do I
do next you'll add your ground coffee to
the filter usually about 2 tablespoons
for every 6 oz of water then you'll
gently pour a small amount of hot water
onto the grounds to let them bloom for
about 30 seconds great thanks what's
bloom bloom blooming allows the coffee
to release gas and enhances the flavor
after blooming slowly pour the rest of
the hot water in a circular motion keep
the water level consistent and let it
drip through the coffee grounds into
your mug cool that sounds great I'll do
the pouring
now awesome take your time and pour
slowly this helps the water extract the
coffee evenly for better flavor anything
I could be doing different or better
about my
technique your technique looks good just
keep a steady gentle pour and make sure
the coffee grounds remain evenly
saturated you're doing great so far
awesome thank you so
much you're welcome it looks like you're
almost done once the cool so in addition
to sharing your phone camera you can
also share what's on your screen so to
test that out I'm going to start a new
conversation hit the advanced voice mode
icon and then go into this little drop-
down menu and hit share screen once I
start the broadcast now chat gbt will
see what I'm showing it and in fact I'm
I'd like to use it to ask for help in
responding to a message so I'm opening
up my messages app and then hey chat GPT
are you seeing my
screen yes I can see it looks like
you're in the messages app how can I
help can you help me respond to this one
or what are you seeing here first
off I see a message from someone asking
if they have what it takes to be a
professional Mall Santa they also sent a
picture of themselves dressed up do you
want to respond to their question I'd
like some help in doing that so how
should I tell Kevin that kindly of
course that he shouldn't quit his day
job you could say something like Hey
Kevin your Santa outfit is looking
festive maybe keep practicing your ho ho
ho and you'll be ready for the mall in
no
time that sounds great uh thanks
you're welcome I'm sure Kevin will
appreciate the encouragement anything
else you'd like help with that's
perfect well I think Kevin makes a great
Santa but you don't need Kevin to talk
to Santa this year starting today and
for the rest of December you can talk to
Santa directly in Chachi BT you can ask
santa anything whether you have
questions about his life at the North
Pool curious about what the elves are up
to or looking for a fun Christmas story
as a parent with curious kids Santa will
respond in real time using his signature
Jolly voice and finding Santa it's super
easy on the home screen just look out
for a snowflake icon that's going to be
your festive entry point you can also
find and select Santa in the chat GPT
settings page all right let's say hi to
Santa hey Santa
oh well hello there it's delightful to
hear from you are you getting excited
for the holidays I'm so excited Santa I
have a question for you what's your
favorite Christmas
tradition what a wonderful question my
favorite Christmas tradition has to be
the magical moment when children hang
their stockings by the fireplace it's
such a warm and cozy tradition filled
with the anticipation of goodies and
surprises what's your favorite holiday
tradition that's a good one Sia and
who's your favorite
reindeer well that's a tricky question
all of my reindeer are special in their
own way Rudolph with his bright red nose
does hold a special place in my heart
because of his Guiding Light but Dasher
dancer praner and all the others are
just as important they each bring their
own magic to the sleigh team do you have
a favorite reindeer Santa I have a
question for you how do I keep my beard
in tiptop
shape maintaining a magnificent beard
takes a bit of magic and care first it's
important to keep it clean and well
groomed a bit of be Santa we need some
real feedback
here now what do you
think that's a fabulous beard it's full
and fluffy just like mine if you give it
a little comb and maybe a Sprinkle of
holiday cheer it will be in tiptop shape
for
Christmas Santa would you say that this
is a great beard or that it's the
greatest
beard that my friend is a magnificent
beard indeed it's truly one of the
greatest beards I've seen full of
holiday spirit and
cheer thank you than
Santa yes what is it my friend all right
let's recap how you can access these
features video and screen share is
rolling out in our latest mobile apps
starting today and over the course of
the next week we'll be rolling out to
all teams users and most plus and pro
pro plus and pro subscribers for plus
and pro subscribers in Europe we will
get this feature to you as soon as we
can if you're on an Enterprise or edu
plan you'll get access early next year
Santa is rolling out over the course of
today globally everywhere you can use
chat GPT voice mode that means you can
talk to Santa on our latest mobile apps
our desktop apps and on desktop web at
chat.com and the first time you talk
with Santa we will reset your advanced
voice usage limits one time so that even
if you've used up your limit for the day
or for the month you can talk with Santa
in advanced voice right away even after
your limits you can also keep chatting
with Santa in standard voice we hope you
enjoy your conversations with Santa as
much as we have all right and just to
wrap up let's get Santa's perspective on
one more thing Santa what's your
favorite Christmas joke
all right what's every elf's favorite
music rap
music a little elf humor for you all
right thanks Santa and I just wanted to
say thanks to the engineers researchers
PMS designers the entire team that's
been working on this for months to bring
it to you we're super excited to see
what you do with it thanks so much and
see you tomorrow Happy holidays